<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Controls Software Engineer Intern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/marathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;controls-software-engineer-intern&#34;&gt;Controls Software Engineer Intern&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting in January 2026, I joined Marathon Fusion in San Francisco as a Controls Software Engineer Intern. Marathon Fusion develops next-generation fuel cycle technologies for fusion energy, including metal foil pumps and plasma centrifuges for tritium processing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I proposed and implemented a full-stack PVAccess-based Python solution to replace LabVIEW, architecting a backend server, REST API gateway, and front-end UI to overhaul the laboratory&amp;rsquo;s data acquisition and control systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full-Stack Software Developer Intern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/dwave/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/dwave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;full-stack-software-developer-intern&#34;&gt;Full-Stack Software Developer Intern&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From May to December 2025, I completed an 8-month co-op at D-Wave Quantum Systems in Burnaby, BC, where I worked as a full-stack software developer on cryogenic control systems for quantum computers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I developed a scalable asynchronous Python server for cryogenic fridge control, interfacing with 10+ SCPI and Modbus devices via a REST API to automate test procedures and log telemetry to an InfluxDB time-series database. On the front-end side, I designed 3+ UI applications in Plotly Dash for remote monitoring, real-time data visualization, and control of server operations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverted Pendulum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects_hp/pendulum_hp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects_hp/pendulum_hp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Led controls software for self-balancing 2 DOF inverted pendulum, implementing real-time C++ firmware on ESP32 microcontroller with nested PID control algorithm in MATLAB Simulink.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Balancing 2 DOF Inverted Pendulum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/pendulum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/pendulum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;self-balancing-2-dof-inverted-pendulum&#34;&gt;Self-Balancing 2 DOF Inverted Pendulum&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This capstone project involved designing and building a self-balancing two degree-of-freedom inverted pendulum from scratch, spanning from September 2024 to April 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I led the controls software for the system, implementing real-time C++ firmware on an ESP32 microcontroller with a nested PID control algorithm designed in MATLAB Simulink. The system stabilizes an inverted pendulum that can move in two independent axes, requiring careful tuning of multiple control loops running simultaneously under hard real-time constraints.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Experimentation Research Intern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/ntt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/ntt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantum-experimentation-research-intern&#34;&gt;Quantum Experimentation Research Intern&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting in May of 2024, I participated in an 8-month long Co-op internship at Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Basic Research Laboratories (BRL) in Atsugi, Kanagawa in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I self-directed optical fiber-based multi-party quantum communication experiments, with the goal of realizing quantum entanglement between multiple users in an optical fiber-based quantum network. I led experiments improving quantum interference visibility between heralded single photon and weak coherent pulse sources. This work was &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.35848/1347-4065/ae35f7&#34;&gt;published in the Japanese Journal of Applied Physics (JJAP)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systems Engineer Intern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/viarail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/viarail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;systems-engineer-intern&#34;&gt;Systems Engineer Intern&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first Co-op internship was a 4-month long experience at VIA Rail Canada&amp;rsquo;s Vancouver Maintenance Center (VMC) during Spring of 2023. Here, I oversaw the implementation as lead project manager of seven continuous improvement projects. By studying and using various continuous improvement methodologies, such as Kaizen, 5S, Six Sigma, Lean Manufacturing and Visual Management, I was able to successfully improve workplace task completion rate by approximately 10% on average.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capacitive Sensor Development Mentee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/qmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/qmi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;capacitive-sensor-development-mentee&#34;&gt;Capacitive Sensor Development Mentee&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;• Designed and fabricated custom flexible capacitive sensor designed to detect proximity and pressure using AutoCAD and SolidWorks, tested using MATLAB and Arduino. Presented findings to non-technical audience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects_hp/enph253_hp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects_hp/enph253_hp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;• Led mechanical design within team of four, designed and fabricated self-driving all-terrain robot from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;• Designed steering geometry in CAD, designed and soldered IR amplifier/detector circuit for use with STM32.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Robot Competition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/enph253/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/enph253/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;enph-253-autonomous-robot-competition&#34;&gt;ENPH 253: Autonomous Robot Competition&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a part of our curriculum for Engineering Physics, students partake in an robotics competition fondly known as &amp;ldquo;Robot Summer&amp;rdquo;, course code ENPH 253: Introduction to Instrument Design. While known as &amp;ldquo;Robot Summer&amp;rdquo;, students are nevertheless expected to take on a full course load, adding up to a total of 18 credits taken during this time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ENPH 253 is a four-month long project course. The first two months are dedicated to design laboratories, where we learned to solder, program an STM32 &amp;ldquo;Blue Pill&amp;rdquo; microprocessor, design and collaborate on CAD using OnShape, interface with digital signals and build Schmidt triggers using comparators, interface with analog signals through building reflective sensors, and finally, build H-bridge circuit to drive DC motors through a PWM signal produced by the STM32.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Competition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/enph353/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/enph353/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;enph-353-machine-learning-competition&#34;&gt;ENPH 353: Machine Learning Competition&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ENPH 353 is a project course taken by UBC Engineering students centered around a machine learning competition. Students in this course practice collaboration through git on a linux-based development environment, image recognition through OpenCV, Optical Character Recognition (OCR) from scratch using Convolutional Neural Networks, robotics control through Robot Operating System and simulation on Gazebo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The competition portion of this course consisted of programming an algorithm for a self-driving car to navigate a simulated environment in Gazebo. The car was expected to traverse on and off road, and navigate obstacles such as roundabouts, pedestrian crosswalks, and other cars. The car was tasked at reading signage along the way, which would give clues to a murder mystery. These clues were to be read using OCR off of a camera mounted at the front of the car, and uploaded to a score tracker during the competition. Each team only had one attempt to run their simulation on-stage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Competition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects_hp/enph353_hp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects_hp/enph353_hp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;• Implemented self-driving and image recognition of a simulated vehicle using OpenCV, PyTorch, Keras, TensorFlow, and ROS in Python, as well as Git and Gazebo on Linux, placing fourth out of eighteen teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
